# Ms. Sahaj Kaur

## Mental Health Therapist

sahajkaur89@gmail.com

Throughout my career, I have contributed to positive results through effective organization, prioritization, and analytical approach. I believe my strengths and qualifications are an ideal match to the required vacancy and will bring immediate value to your esteem Organization.

In my former Mental Health trainer cum Counselor role, I exercise a calculated and methodical approach to problem solving. While I am independently motivated, I appreciate collective efforts and collaborate productively within group settings. Moreover, I am competent in project management and project reporting with proficiency in schedule and timeline management.

This opportunity is especially exciting as my professional goals align with organization's mission and values. Further, my communication, innovation, and leadership abilities will serve to support your continued organizational efforts.

To illustrate the scope of my career history and professional competencies, please take a moment to review my enclosed resume. I am grateful for your evaluation of my credentials and subsequent response.

## SAHAJ KAUR

**Phone:** +91 8319681159

Email:sahajkaur89@gmail.com

Address: House no 61, Nainagiri, BHOPAL, 462023 (IN)

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Hard-working professional with 3+ years of experience and a proven knowledge of case management, data collection and analysis, and public health administration. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill the Mid-level job role at your company.

Dedicated Psychologist equipped with an array of skills and knowledge in the areas of substance abuse, crisis response and intervention, and group therapy. Extensive experience working in both clinical and school settings providing counseling to children, adolescents, and adults.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Mental health Trainer cum Counselor ICall Psychosocial Helpline, TISS, Mumbai/UNFPA Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh Oct. 2018 – Apr. 2020

Job responsibility includes -

- · Survey administration and preparing questionnaire for health workers and district counselors
- Training health workers about counseling skills and health related concerns.
- Capacity building which includes co-ordination with Directors' and Mission Director of NHM, of the state; co-coordinating with District Program officer and Block Program officers'.
- · Preparing the format essential for the assessment of individual during training
- · Analyzing the data and preparing and presenting the necessary stats and report with the State and concerned authorities
- · Supervision and monitoring of the state counselors deputed in the district hospitals

#### Junior Counselor Palakk Institute of Learning/ Model Govt School

BHOPAL, Madhya Pradesh

Jan. 2018 – Sep. 2018

- Worked in project "Personality enhancement through Positive Parenting" under Board of Secondary Education, Bhopal for developing training Students from Standard 9th to 12th including personal sessions.
- Interact with clients to assist them in gaining insight, defining goals, and planning action to achieve effective personal, social, educational, and vocational development and adjustment.
- Counsel individuals and groups regarding problems, such as stress, substance abuse, and family situations, to modify behavior or to improve personal, social, and vocational adjustment.

#### **CONTENT WRITER**

Salma prabhu Institute of Counseling

Mumbai, Maharashtra Aug. 2017 – Nov. 2017

Worked for Salma Prabhu Institute of Counseling as content writer and editor for preparing book on teenage Counseling . Also conducted personal sessions for teenagers

English Mentor Gofodu BHOPAL, Madhya Pradesh

Jan. 2017 – Jul. 2017

Have worked for an online education portal that helps student prepare for various competitive examination like Gate, CLAT, banking;in which I have prepared videos to help students learn basic English covering wide aspect from grammar till interview preparation.

#### **EDUCATION**

May. 2020

**Master of Arts: Psychology** 

• Barkatulla University - BHOPAL, Madhya Pradesh

Jun. 2017

**Bachelor of Arts: Psychology** 

• IGNOU - BHOPAL, Madhya Pradesh

#### **Relevant Coursework**

2016

MBBS (Third year Drop-out)

### **High School Diploma**

**May 2009** 

ST JOSPEHS' CONVENT S S SCHOOL, Jabalpur, Madhya Pradesh

## **Awards & Honors**

Certificate in Personal Counseling	2018
Diploma in Nutrition and Health education	2017
School Reporter	2005

## **SKILLS**

Hardworking

Expert

Capacity building

Experienced

Problem Solving approach

Skillful

Communication skills

Expert

Project Management

Experienced